ROBERT FARLEY

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Phone: (570)-209-6717 Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/robertfarley89 Email: rfarley89@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/Nomad-Rob Website: NomadRob.com Location: Tulsa, Oklahoma

SUMMARY

Skilled software developer with a track record of successful projects. Strong problem-solving and communication in different career fields. Passionate about continuous learning with collaboration and collaboration, ready to contribute to software development teams. Experienced with team leadership. Completed over 120 projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript	Bootstrap	Python	MySQL	Git/GitHub
ReactJS	HTML & CSS	Node.js	Linux/UNIX	JSON
jQuery	Docker	MongoDB	RESTful API	Vite

PROJECTS

Museum of Imagination (Dec 2023) Team Project

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/Nomad-Rob/Museum_of_the_Imagination

- Given a theme of a museum of imagination, created a Christmas themed experience.
- Primary role during project Project Manager, Three.JS scene, Hosting, and Gift shop page.

Technologies - JavaScript, Firebase, Three.js, SCSS, JSON, Vite, HTML & CSS, GitHub.

Website Link - https://museum-of-the-imagination.web.app/

Airplane Above (Nov 2023) Solo Project

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/Nomad-Rob/Solo_Hackathon/tree/main/Airplane_Above

- Developed an innovative application utilizing geolocation technology to collect real-time data on the closest aircraft to the user's location, enhancing situational awareness and streamlining decision making processes.
- Utilized an API to gather ADS-B details and show using users location.

Technologies - JavaScript, Python, HTML & CSS, GitHub.

Wes's Cozy Kitchen (Sept 2023) Team Project

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/Nomad-Rob/Hack_Sprint-Breakfast

- Developed a Python program utlizing Pygame library during a Hacksprint with a breakfast theme.
- Primary role during project was Database and Game Logic.

Technologies - Python, Pygame, GitHub, Linux.

AirBnB Clone (Aug 2023) Team Project

GitHub Repo - https://github.com/Nomad-Rob/holbertonschool-AirBnB_clone_v4

- Developed a fully functional Airbnb clone web application from scratch, showcasing proficiency in full-stack web development.
- Implemented user authentication, property listing, and booking functionalities, creating an interactive and user-friendly platform.

Technologies - Python, MySQL, jQuery, Flask, JavaScript, JSON, HTML & CSS, Linux, GitHub.

ROBERT FARLEY

WORK EXPERIENCE

Oklahoma Army National Guard

2006-2023

- UH60M Helicopter Pilot 2020-2023
 - Proficient in diverse aircraft missions including Troop, Movement, Sling Loads, Assault,
 Water Buckets with hundreds of hours in the aircraft.
 - Utilized skills such as Flight Planning, Pre-flight checks, Mentorship, Navigation, System Management, Emergency Procedures, and Monitor in-flight data.
- Oklahoma Counterdrug Ground Recon Team Leader (2016–2019)
 - Led a 6-10 man unit in support of law enforcement with counter narcotic operations in rural and urban environments in Oklahoma in over 100 missions.
 - o Utilized photography, audio, and video surveillance as well as infiltration techniques.
 - Served as the subject matter expert for Oklahoma's Ground team in support of law enforcement with participation in over \$45,000,000 seized throughout my tenor.
- Sniper/Scout Platoon Sergeant (2006-2020)
 - o Trained and led 32 soldiers in various training, combat operations, and mentorship.
 - Deployed multiple times, competed in International Joint Service Sniper competitions.
 - o Fostered Multi-National relationships with foreign entities.

Aegis/GardaWorld Federal Services

Designated Defensive Marksman/Protective Security Specialist

2019-2020

- Performed protective security functions for key Department of State personnel while in Kabul Afghanistan.
- Conducted pre site surveys on over 25 locations while in a high security posture or low visibility operations.
- Successfully maintained over 95% qualifications on over 10 weapon systems quarterly.

Xerox Business Solutions Southwest (Apple Contract)

Senior Technical Advisor

2015-2016

- Managed a team of 20 or more personnel to successfully provide exceptional support and resolution to ongoing technical issues while maintaining certain metrics.
- Directly coordinated with iOS and CPU engineers through help desk tickets to provide issue resolution with a 97% resolution rate.

EDUCATION

Atlas School

Diploma - Computer Science & Full-Stack Web Development

Rigorous 20 month computer science and software engineering school that is project and peer-learning bases. Anticipated Graduation - August 2024.

OTHER